A Finding Aid to the Rose Fried Gallery Records, 1936-1972, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Rose Fried Gallery Records
1936-1972
bulk 1945-1970
Archives of American Art
Rose Fried Gallery (New York, N.Y.)
AAA.rosefrig
Archival Resource Key
8.1 Linear feet
The Rose Fried Gallery records measure 8.1 linear feet and date from 1936 to 1972 with the bulk of materials dating from 1945 to 1970. The majority of the collection consists of artists files documenting the gallery's relationship with abstract, modern, and Latin American artists; additional named subject files; and scattered administrative and financial files. Individual artists and subject files contain a wide variety of documentation, such as correspondence, photographs, financial records, and printed materials.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Rose Fried Gallery Records were donated by Rose Fried and her brother and executor Paul Fried in multiple accretions between 1968 and 1974.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as two series.
Missing Title
Series 1: General Administrative Records, 1947-1970 (9 folders; Box 1)
Series 2: Artists' and Clients' Files, 1936-1972 (7.9 linear feet; Boxes 1-8, OV 9)
Conditions Governing Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Washington, D.C. Research Center. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy also requires advance notice. Contact Reference Services for more information.
Historical Note
Rose Fried established the Rose Fried Gallery in the 1940s in New York City, New York. Fried established the gallery when she took over the Pinacotheca Gallery owned by Dan Harris. The Gallery specialized in abstract and modern art, and represented cubists, futurists, Dadaists, and masters of Latin American art. The Rose Fried Gallery was instrumental in introducing the American public to many abstract painters, including Mondrian and Kandinsky. The Gallery remained operational until Fried's death in 1970.
Scope and Contents
The Rose Fried Gallery records measure 8.1 linear feet and date from 1936 to 1972 with the bulk of materials dating from 1945 to 1970. The majority of the collection consists of artists files documenting the gallery's relationship with abstract, modern, and Latin American artists; additional named subject files; and scattered administrative and financial files. Individual artists and subject files contain a wide variety of documentation, such as correspondence, photographs, financial records, and printed materials.
Scattered administrative records document the founding and history of the Rose Fried Gallery, biographical materials about Rose Fried, as well as scattered administrative correspondence, press releases, and gallery catalogs. There are two sound recordings of interviews with Rose Fried in which she discusses the origins of the Rose Fried Gallery and some of the gallery's shows.
The bulk of the records consist of alphabetical artists' and clients' files documenting the gallery's dealings with individual artists, clients, other galleries, museums, and universities. Contents of individual files vary but may include correspondence, contractual agreements, financial records, printed material, and photographs. A few of the artists represented in the files include Olle Baertling, Joseph Cornell, Ben Cunningham, Sonia Delaunay, Sorel Etrog, John Ferren, Raymond Hendler, Wassily Kandinsky, Stanton MacDonald-Wright, Piet Mondrian, Russell Morgan, Francis Picabia, Hans Richter, Joaquin Torres-Garcia, and Jean Xceron, among many others.
Existence and Location of Copies
The collection is available on 35 mm microfilm reels 2200-2209, and N69-37 at the Archives of American Art offices and through interlibrary loan. Researchers should note that the arrangement of the material described in the container inventory does not reflect the arrangement of the collection on microfilm.
Some of the sound recordings in this collection have been copied for research access and digital copies are available in the Archives of American Art offices.
Photographs; Sound recordings; Painting, Modern -- 20th century -- New York (State) -- New York; Hispanic American artists; Interviews; Art, Abstract; Art galleries, Commercial -- New York (State); Kandinsky, Wassily, 1866-1944; Mondrian, Piet, 1872-1944; Macdonald-Wright, Stanton, 1890-1973; Xceron, Jean, 1890-1967; Fried, Rose; Baertling, Olle, 1911-1981; Hendler, Raymond, 1923-; Torres-García, Joaquín, 1874-1949; Cunningham, Ben, 1904-1975; Richter, Hans, 1888-1976; Delaunay, Sonia; Pinacotheca Gallery (New York, N.Y.); Cornell, Joseph; Morgan, Russell; Ferren, John, 1905-1970; Picabia, Francis, 1879-1953; Etrog, Sorel, 1933-
- General Administrative Records, 1947-1970; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 9 Folders Box 1
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains writings concerning the founding and the history of the Rose Fried Gallery, biographical records about Rose Fried, scattered correspondence and financial records, writings, printed materials. Included are two recorded interviews with Rose Fried where she discusses the origins of the Rose Fried Gallery and some of the gallery's exhibitions.
  - Founding/History, 1956-1970; Archival Resource Key; Includes 1 sound cassette and 2 sound tape reels. (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
  - Financial Material, 1961-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - General Gallery Correspondence, 1947-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Printed Material, 1947-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7-9)
- Artists and Clients Files, 1936-1972; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 7.9 Linear feet Boxes 1-8, OV 9
  Artists and Client Files are comprised of individual files for artists, galleries, museums, and universities that had dealings with the Rose Fried Gallery. Artists represented include cubists, futurists, Dadaists, and masters of Latin American Art. Material is comprised of contracts, loan agreements, financial material, correspondence, press releases, news clippings, exhibition catalogs, and photographs.
  Particularly rich files are found for Olle Baertling, Sorel Etrog, John Ferren, Stanton MacDonald-Wright, Joaquin Torres-Garcia, and Jean Xceron. The Olle Baertling file includes one sound recording.
  - Adler, Samuel, 1963-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ajay, Abe, 1963-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
  - Albright-Knox Gallery, 1961-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Alcopley, 1957-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Andrews, Stephen, 1964-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Arnholm, Ronald, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Arp, Jean, 1953-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Art Association of Newport, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Asback, Hugo, 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - A Miscellaneous, 1960-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Baertling, Olle, Correspondence, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Baertling, Olle, Correspondence, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Baertling, Olle, Correspondence, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Baertling, Ollie. "Architecture in the Space Age" WYNC radio program with guest Olle Baertling and host Jeffrey Ellis Aronin. Broadcast February 6, 1967., Archival Resource Key; Includes 1 sound tape reel. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Baertling, Olle, Correspondence, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Baertling, Olle, Correspondence, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Baertling, Olle, Correspondence, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Baertling, Olle, Press Releases, circa 1963-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Baertling, Olle, Print Material, circa 1963-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Baertling, Olle, Writings On, 1958-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Baertling, Olle, 1958-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Baertling, Olle, 1958-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Baertling, Olle, 1958-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Baertling, Olle, 1958-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Bakalar, Mr. and Mrs. David, 1961-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Balla, Giacoma, 1953-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2-4)
  - Bate, Stanley, 1965-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Baum, Mark, 1963-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Baumbach, Harold, 1941-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bayer, Herbert, 1962-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Beasley, Bruce, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Besner, Jacques, 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Binder, Joseph, 1965-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Birla Academy of Art and Culture, 1967-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Bolotowsky, Ilya, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Boxer, Stanley, 1967-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 14-18)
  - Bloedel, Lawrence, 1965-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Bourgeois, Louise, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Brown, Eve and Harper, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Buchheister, Carl, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Buchholz, Erick, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - B Miscellaneous, 1960-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Cammas, Jacques, 1959-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Carva, C., undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Carter, Clarence, 1965-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Chandra, Aninash, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Chin, Hsiao, 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 29-30)
  - Clerc, Pierre, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Cook, Dr. John, 1967-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Cornell, Joseph, 1961-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Cox, Margaret, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - C Miscellaneous, 1960-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Dangelo, Sergio, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Daura, Pierre, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Day, Mr. and Mrs. Lee, 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Davis, Stuart, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - de Caro, Anita, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - de Chirico, G., 1959-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - de Conick, Suzanne, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Delaunay, Robert, 1960-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Delaunay, Sonia, Correspondence and Printed Material, 1955-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Delaunay, Sonia, Photographs of Artist and Artwork, circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - de Menil, John, 1961-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Dombek, Blanche, 1960-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Dorazio, Piero and Virginia, 1956-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 49-50)
  - Dreier, Katherine S., 1939-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 51-52)
  - Duchamp, Marcel, 1950-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Dunkelman Gallery, 1961-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - D Miscellaneous, 1950-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Edinburgh, Dorothy, 1964-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Elliott, Ronnie, 1959-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 57-58)
  - Ellis, R.C., 1967-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Ernst, Max, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Etrog, Sorel, 1962-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
  - E Miscellaneous, 1961-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Ferren, John, 1957-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8-16)
  - Fernandez, Guillermo, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Fleischmann, Adolf, 1967-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Frankenthaler, Helen, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Freemantle, Christopher, 1967-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - F Miscellaneous, 1961-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Galantiere, Lewis, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Geigy Chemical Corporation, 1965-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Gilioli, Emile, 1947-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Gleizes, Albert, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Goldowsky Gallery, 1964-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Gorky, Arshile, 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Graham, Donald, 1963-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 28-29)
  - Graham, John, 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Gris, Juan, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Grossberg, Jacob, General, 1963-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Grossberg, Jacob, Photographs, 1963-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Guevara, José, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Guggenheim Museum, 1961-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Guston, Philip, 1960-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Guy, James, 1964-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - G Miscellaneous, 1943-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Hahn, Nonie, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Hanover Gallery, 1958-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Hansegger, John K., 1947-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - Harms, Elizabeth, 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Harvey, Jacqueline, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Hausmann, Raoul, 1948-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Hazen, Joseph, 1959-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Hendler, Raymond, 1960-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 7-9)
  - Henning, Edward B., 1960-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Hillman, Kay M., 1951-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Hirshhorn, Joseph H., 1962-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Hoch, Hannah, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Hoowij, Jan, 1960-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - H Miscellaneous, 1961-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Israel, Murray, 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - I and J Miscellaneous, 1961-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Kandinsky, Wassily, 1960-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Karsakaya, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Katz, Paul, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Kiesler, Lillian, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Klee, Paul, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Kloss, Koshick, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Krajcberg, Franz, 1958-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 24-25)
  - Krannert Art Museum, 1965-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Kubiceck, Juro, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Kunstwerk, Das, 1961-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Kupka, Francois, 1957-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - K Miscellaneous, 1958-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Lacagnina, Arnaldo, 1967-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Lacasse, Joseph, 1955-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 32-33)
  - Laros, Fred, 1962-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Lassaw, Ibram, 1962-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Lefebre Gallery, 1961-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Lefebvre-Foinet, Lucien, 1954-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Leger, Ferdinand, 1960-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Lewitin, Landes, 1941-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Lewitin, Landes: Artwork, 1941-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Lewitin, Landes: Artwork (Duplicates), 1941-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Liebau, Ariadna, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Lipchitz, Jacques, 1941-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Lissitzky, El, 1947-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Los Angeles County Museum, 1961-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Lowe Art Gallery, 1964-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - L Miscellaneous, 1961-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - MacDonald-Wright, Stanton, 1955-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 48-54)
  - MacDonald-Wright, Stanton, 1955-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1-7)
  - Malevich, Kasimir, 1952-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Mansauroff, P., undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Manso, Leo, 1963-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 10-13)
    Oversized material housed in OV 9.
  - Manus, Adele, 1959-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Maremont, Arnold H., 1957-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Martin, Knox, 1963-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Massine, Leonide, 1957-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 17-21)
  - Matisse, Henri, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Matisse Gallery, 1965-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - McEwen, Jean Albert, 1965-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - McFadden, Elizabeth, 1961-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Metzinger, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Miller, J. Pindyck, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Miro, Joan, 1936-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Mittell, Berenice, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Mondrian, Piet, 1951-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Mondrian, Piet, Exhibition Catalogues and Printed Material, 1951-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Mondrian, Piet, Photographs of Works of Art, 1951-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1957-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - M Miscellaneous, 1961-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - New York University, 1960-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Nicholson, Ben, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - N Miscellaneous, 1961-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Old Chaham, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Olds, Lawrence B., 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - O Miscellaneous, 1958-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Peinado, Joaquin, 1960-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Perrin, Gertrude, 1943-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Pharr, Mr. and Mrs. Walter, 1961-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Picabia, Francis, 1951-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 44-45)
  - Picasso, Pablo, 1952-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 46-47)
  - Porter, David, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - P Miscellaneous, 1961-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Quinlivan, Kevin, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Quirt, Walter, 1961-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Racoosin, Theodore, 1964-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Rawlings, Mr. and Mrs. John, 1960-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Reid, Robert, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Rhode Island School of Design, 1965-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Richter, Hans, 1960-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Robbins, Louis J., 1960-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
  - Russell, Mrs. Charles, 1965-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Russell, Morgan - Correspondence, 1959-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Russell, Morgan - Printed Material, 1932-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Russell, Morgan - Photographs, circa 1950-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - R Miscellaneous, 1961-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Salvatore, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Schillinger, Joseph, 1941-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Schlemmer, Oscar, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Schnabel, Day, 1952-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Schwartz, Galleria d'Arte, 1961-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Schwitters, Kurt, 1947-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 15-16)
  - Segy Gallery, 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Seitz, William C., 1964-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Seupher, Michel, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Severini, Giro, 1950-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 20-22)
  - Shoren, Ken, 1963-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Signori, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Sirak, Dr. and Mrs. Howard, 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Sironi, Mario, 1961-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Soloway, Ann, 1958-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Stillman, Ary and Frances, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Strick, Racelle, 1966-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 29-30)
  - Suro, Dario, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - S Miscellaneous, 1957-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 32-33)
  - Terry, Alice, 1962-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Thepot, Roger and Francois, 1959-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Thomas, Yvonne, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Thompson, J. Walter, 1963-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Tobey, Mark, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Torres, Augusto, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Torres, Horatio, 1958-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Torres-Garcia, Joaquin, 1937-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 41-47)
  - Torres-Garcia, Joaquin, 1937-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 1-19)
  - Tower, Mrs. Roderick, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Trivigno, Pat, 1965-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 21-22)
  - Tryggvadottir, Nina, 1961-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - T Miscellaneous, 1965-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - University of Notre Dame, 1962-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - U Miscellaneous, 1961-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Van Brunt, Philip, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Van Doesburg, Theo, 1947-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Van Velde, Geer, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Vantongerbo, George, 1953-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Vieillard, Roger, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Villon, Jacques, 1943-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Vincente, Esteban, 1958-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Visser, Carel, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Von Berann, Lawrence, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Von Ringelheim, Paul, 1962-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1-5)
  - Von Weigand, Charmion, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 6)